# DenysPotapov

PHP developer

#### contact

+38 050 330-20-57
 denys.potapov
 in denyspotapov
denys.potapov@gmail.com

#### **PHP skills**

Phalcon, Silex, MySQL, PHPUnit, codeception, composer, TravisCI

#### front end skills

JavaScript, AngularJs HTML, CSS (SCSS), grunt

#### other skills

git, python, go

### languages

bilingual Ukrainian/Russian intermediate English basic German

# profile

I am a developer with over 9 years experience working on a variety of projects from conception to delivery. I am conversant in a wide range of technologies, now focused on PHP web development, follow the latest industry trends with great interest (OOP, PSR, SCSS, HTML5). My approach is methodical but creative. I am comfortable working either independently or as part of a team.

## education

2002–2008 **M.Sc. degree in Computer Science**Specialization in computer systems and robotics

# **experience**

2012—Present	<b>barzo.com.ua</b> Creating and launching a start-up company. Developing from the ground e-commerce platform (PHP, MySql, HTML, SCSS). Working with and managing team of 3 freelancers.
2012—Present	<b>Qport</b> Creating a large network of digital signage systems (biggest project with 8000 screens). Integrating ERP system in retail stores (15 stores).
2009—2012	<b>Qport</b> Developing interactive screens software (python). Developing an ERP system for retail stores (1c ERP).
2008—2009	<b>Physics-technological institute</b> Development and integration of foundry process modeling system (Object Pascal) for perspective developments department institute of metals and alloys of the National academy of science of Ukraine
2005—2007	<b>Proling Office</b> Development of machine translation system ProlingOffice (C#) and it's

## awards

August 2014	IQLab Challenge PHP back end development	2 <sup>nd</sup> place
November 2013	<b>UA Web Challenge V</b> Back end development	3 <sup>rd</sup> place
	<b>Codingame oDesk Contest</b> python developers	5 <sup>th</sup> place

online version (ASP.NET)

### skills

advanced PHP back end development

• Modern PHP frameworks (Phalcon, Silex);

• SQL (MySQL, PDO);

• Code testing (PHPUnit, codeception);

• Continuous integration (composer, TravisCI);

• Version control systems (git, git-flow).

intermediate front end development

JavaScript, AngularJs, HTML, CSS (SCSS), grunt

basic **python, go** 

## languages

native Russian/Ukrainian

intermediate **English** conversationally fluent

basic German basic words and phrases only

# community

blogging habrahabr.ru

Top-100 author in biggest Russian-speaking IT community

speaking IT conferences

Taking part in local IT conferences as visor and speaker. ('Object Calis-

thenics in php' at WebCamp Developer Day on youtube).

open source PHP password generator library

Library has 24 stars on github and more then 30 download on packag-

ist

## interests

volunteer Running a code club

Code-club in Kyiv is a part of network of volunteer-led after school cod-

ing clubs for children aged 9-11

running